Guide to the Familias Unidas Por La Justicia Records and Ephemera
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Familias Unidas por la Justicia records and ephemera
2012-2018
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
6251
Familias Unidas por la Justicia
1.53 cubic feet 3 boxes, 1 oversize folder, 1 banner
870 digital files (3.02 gigabytes)
Records and ephemera of an independent farmworker union comprised of Mixteco and Triqui families in Washington State
Familias Unidas por la Justicia (FUJ), is farmworker union comprised of Mixteco and Triqui families. In 2015, FUJ affiliated with the Washington State Labor Council, AFL-CIO.
Organized into 3 accessions.
Accession No. 6251-001, Familias Unidas por la Justicia records and ephemera, 2012-2017
Accession No. 6251-002, Familias Unidas por la Justicia records and ephemera, approximately 2013-2018
Accession No. 6251-003, Familias Unidas por la Justicia banner, 2012
Emphera, picket signs, flyers, correspondence, meeting notes, a berry package, stickers, digital photographs, videos, and documents from Familias Unidas por la Justicia's work organizing farmworkers in Whatcom County. Some materials relate to Community to Community Development, a grassroots organization that worked closely with the workers of FUJ during its history. Highlights of the collection includes materials from FUJ's organizing, strike, boycott, and contract victory against Sakuma Brothers, Inc., a berry grower in Mount Vernon, Washington where many of the FUJ workers were employed and lived.
Open to all users, but access to portions of the collection is restricted. Contact Special Collections for details.
Familias Unidas por la Justicia$vArchives; Community to Community Development (Organization)$vCorrespondence; Sakuma Brothers Farms; Strikes and lockouts$xAgricultural laborers$zWashington (State); Boycotts$zWashington (State); Labor unions$zWashington (State); Agricultural laborers$zWashington (State); Photographs; Ephemera; Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Agriculture; Labor Unions; Mexican Americans
- Familias Unidas por la Justicia records and ephemera, 2012-2017; 6251-001; 1.3 cubic feet (2 boxes, 1 oversize folder); 576 digital files (2.02 gigabytes)
  Emphera, picket signs, flyers, correspondence, meeting notes, a berry package, stickers, digital photographs, videos, and documents from Familias Unidas por la Justicia's work organizing farmworkers in Whatcom County. Some materials relate to Community to Community Development, a grassroots organization that worked closely with the workers of FUJ during its history. Highlights of the collection includes materials from FUJ's organizing, strike, boycott, and contract victory against Sakuma Brothers, Inc., a berry grower in Mount Vernon, Washington where many of the FUJ workers were employed and lived.
  Open to all users, but access to portions of the collection is restricted. Contact Special Collections for details. No user access copy is currently available for the digital materials. Arrangements can be made to preview the media onsite in the Special Collections Reading Room by contacting Special Collections well in advance of your visit. Users may be able to obtain a reproduction of the material for a fee by contacting Special Collections.
  - Digital materials, undated; 576 digital files (2.02 gigabytes) (Electronic file Offline)
  - Agreement between Sakuma Brothers Farms, INC, and Familias Unidas por la Justicia, 2017 (Box 1)
    One copy each in English and Spanish
  - Klipsun magazine, 2014 (Box 1)
    Includes an article on the Sakuma Brothers farm
  - Miscellaneous documents, approximately 2017 (Box 1)
    Article, call script, flyers, and article 11: secretary-treasurer
  - Notebook, 2016 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous documents, approximately 2013-2016 (Box 1)
    Drafts, blank ballots, thank you card, signatures of support, notes, correspondence, press release, Sakuma job application, and articles
  - Articles, approximately 2015 (Box 1)
    Articles on issues of activism and human rights, not about FUJ or Sakuma Brothers
  - FUJ Tour honorarium forms signed, 2016 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous documents, 2013-2016 (Box 1)
    Article, notes, correspondence, flyer, sticker, and memoradum of understanding/agreement
  - Member and voting information, 2016 (Box 1)
    Access restricted: material should be reviewed for personal information
  - Miscellaneous documents, approximately 2016 (Box 1)
    Notes, correspondence, drawing, member lists, newsletters, and timeline
  - Sakuma documents, 2013-2015 (Box 1)
    Blank applications and employee manual
  - Miscellaneous documents, approximately 2016-2017 (Box 1)
    Articles, notes
  - FUJ July 11 2015 (Box 1)
    Notes and correspondence
  - Miscellaneous documents, 2013-2016 (Box 1)
    Notes, articles, employee packet, disciplinary notice, calendar, flyer, and correspondence
  - CD: "Ballad of Sakuma Farms" by Gary Kanter, 2016 (Box 1)
  - Sign, posters, and art, undated (Box 2)
  - Signs, undated (Box 2)
  - Berry package with sticker, undated (Box 2)
  - Signs, undated (Mapcase:oversize Map case drawer E41)
- Familias Unidas por la Justicia records and ephemera, approximately 2013-2018; 6251-002; 0.23 cubic feet (1 box); 294 digital files (1 gigabyte)
  Emphera, flyers, correspondence, meeting notes, stickers, digital photographs, and documents from Familias Unidas por la Justicia's work organizing farmworkers in Whatcom County. Some materials relate to Community to Community Development, a grassroots organization that worked closely with the workers of FUJ during its history. Highlights of the collection include materials from FUJ's organizing, strike, boycott, and contract victory against Sakuma Brothers, Inc., a berry grower in Mount Vernon, Washington where many of the FUJ workers were employed and lived.
  No restrictions on access for paper-based materials. No user access copy is currently available for the digital materials. Arrangements can be made to preview the digital materials onsite in the Special Collections Reading Room by contacting Special Collections well in advance of your visit. Users may be able to obtain a reproduction of the material for a fee by contacting Special Collections.
  Donated by Jason Holland, who served as chief negotiator of FUJ's contract and was an organizer and supporter from the start of the FUJ campaign in 2013.
  - Digital materials, 2013-2016; 294 digital files (1 gigabyte) (Electronic file Offline)
  - Records and ephemera, 2013-2018 (Box 1)
- Familias Unidas por la Justicia banner, 2012; 6251-003; One banner
  Banner created by Familias Unidas por la Justice during the Sakuma Brothers union organizing campaign. FUJ marched behind it and used it in dozens of rallies and actions. Banner reads "Support Farmworkers: Boycott Sakuma Berries boycottsakumaberries.com"
  Access restricted: For terms of access, contact University of Washington Libraries Special Collections.
  Donated by Jason Holland, who was chief contract negotiator and an organizer and volunteer with FUJ since the start of their campaign